Prasanna Prabhakaran

Location: Dubai

Mobile: +971 509407844 LinkedIn: prasannaraja

Email: prasannaraja@msn.com

Summary:

10 Years of Application Development Experience

- Randstad Private Limited, India (Senior .NET Specialist)
- Raqmiyat LLC, UAE (Senior .NET Specialist)
- Cognizant Technologies, London (Associate)
- HCL Technologies, India (Senior Software Engineer)
- Inatech, India (Consultant)
- Anna University (BE.CSE Fulltime Program)



Im a lead developer, i have work experience with consulting service and product based companies in software development. I worked in **London** for a year as a lead developer and individual contributor with a Leading IT Firm in **UAE**

Skills

.NET Web Application Development

Angular 9, RxJs, .NET Core, ASP.NET MVC, Web APIs,Azure Cloud (DevOps), C#, EF 4.5, WCF, Web services (SOAP & REST), Linq, JQuery, JavaScript patterns, KendoUI, Bootstrap, MS SQL Server

Reports

QAP (Qlik Analytical Platform), QlikView, Qlik Sense, Mashup API, NPrinting, JasperSoft Bi Tool, High Chart, High Stocks, SSRS

Version Control

GIT, TFS, SVN, VSTS, TFVC, CI/CD

Payment Gateway Integration

E-Dirham, PayPal

Experience

Randstad Private Limited

Senior .NET Specialist - 2020 - 2021

Capital Cost Estimating Tool is a key application for Shell Private Limited for predicting the cost invloved for building constructions in sea bed, this application is a key service which exposes api for all other application which depends on them

- Individual Contributor, Angular Component development
- Developed the application using Angular 9, Material UI, RxJs, PrimeNg, C#, ASP.NET Core, WebApi, Entity Framework, LINQ, SQL Server 2012, Git Repository
- · CI/CD in Azure DevOps, Managing Pipelines, Auto deployment based on approval

- · Version Control using Git, preer reviews and approvals
- · Developed many reusable component for the swift development

Raqmiyat LLC, UAE

Senior .NET Specialist - 2018 - 2019

Health Insurance Portal is a service where user can search for the registered online insurance products based on specific needs such as annual coverage, international coverage, type of room, doctor fees, medicine sub- limit or a specific health treatment coverage, this search can be accessed by public and Health insurance companies.

- Individual Contributor, Greenfield Application
- Developed the application using Angular 6, C#, ASP.NET Core, Entity Framework, LINQ, SQL Server 2012,WCF, web API, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- CI/CD in Azure DevOps, Managing Pipelines, Auto deployment based on approval
- Version Control migrated from TFS to Azure DevOps
- Implemented Payment through E-Dirham, which is the government's official payment gateway.

Cognizant Technologies Solutions

Associate - 2014 - 2018

- · Lead Developer, Individual Contributor, Worked in London for a year
- · Analyzed user needs and developed software solutions
- Project involves AngularJS 1.68, QlikView, C#, Linq, WCF, MVC, JSON, Sql server 2008 R2
- TDD Environment experience
- · Development, Debugging and Troubleshooting Issues
- Qlik Sense Development, Mashup API integration with AngularJs Application & Documentum Server

HCL Technologies, India

Senior Software Engineer - 2014 - 2014

- Worked on Application Development
- Project involves MVC 4,ASP.NET,C#, WebApi, Sql Server 2008
- · Banking Project

Inatech Info Solutions, India

Consultant - 2010 - 2013

BunkerTech is a SAAS application which is planned to be released in 2013 which will have modules such as Procurement, Trade Risk Management, and Admin. Since it is a SAAS application, it is built with multi-tenancy feature.

- Individual Contributor, SAAS Product, Multitenancy, JasperSoft Report
- Project Involves ASP.NET MVC 3,C#, WCF, Entity Framework 4.0, Linq, JQuery 1.8, Kendo UI, SQL Server, JasperSoft
- · Oil & Bunkering Product

Projects

Shell India Private Limited. Bangalore (July 2020 – till date). Lead Developer,
 Angular 9, RxJs ASP.NET Core, C#.net application, Git,Azure DevOps,Sql Server

2019

- Department of Health. Abu Dhabi (Nov 2018 Dec 2019). Lead Developer,
 Developed core modules, Payment Gateway Integration and SMART PASS with Angular 6, ASP.NET Core, C#.net application
- Injazat Data Systems, Abu Dhabi (Nov 2018 Dec 2019). Lead Developer, Product Enhancements, MVC C#.net application
- XL Catlin, Inc. UK (2016 Sep 2018). Lead Developer, Developed core modules, Qlik Sense Development and Mashup API integration with Angularis, MVC C#.net application
- SunTrust Bank, USA (2016). Developed modules for financial wellness program in strict deadline, Integration with SharePoint.
- US Bank, USA (2016). Developed modules for Money Movement Program, Online banking, Mobile & Desktop development platform.
- Aetna, Inc. USA (2015). Developed modules for Active Care Team application for Quality Measurement of Health care insurance provider service.
- Standard Chartered Bank, Singapore (2014-2015). Developed Information
 Delivery System for communicating bank transaction data's to countries regulatory compliance system.
- BunkerTech, UK (2012-2013). SAAS based web application built on MVC3.0, Entity Framework 4.0, Linq, JQuery 1.8, Kendo UI, where multiple users can use simultaneously create and track their orders.
- P4u[Phones4u], UK (2011 2012). Orange Data link evolution is POS client forward orders to Orange Mobile Store Service .POS client is used by the store to buy, upgrade mobile phone and plans contracts of Orange Service. C#.NET, SQL, XML, Web service 2.0, javascript
- Hutchison 3G, UK (2010-2011). Upgraded with 3D secure transaction method to avoid fraudulent purchase.

Education

Anna University - Sri Venkateshwara College of Engineering

Major: Bachelor Degree in Computer Science Engineering

Mode: Fulltime Program

Central Polytechnic College, Chennai

Major: Diploma in Electronics and Communication engineering

Mode: Fulltime Program

References

Available on request